<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>longway2go</title>
    <link>http://longway2go.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:56:59 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>http://hexo.io/</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Grandmother Ask Me To Tell You She&#39;s Sorry</title>
      <link>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/09/04/My-Grandmother-Ask-Me-To-Tell-You-She-s-Sorry-md/</link>
      <guid>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/09/04/My-Grandmother-Ask-Me-To-Tell-You-She-s-Sorry-md/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 06:50:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;I recently read this book - &lt;code&gt;My Grandmother Ask Me To Tell You She&amp;#39;s Sorry&lt;/code&gt;, and I love it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book tells us the
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I recently read this book - <code>My Grandmother Ask Me To Tell You She&#39;s Sorry</code>, and I love it. </p><p>This book tells us the story how a girl overcome her fear and grows up, with her granny be her spiritual mentor. I’m touched by the missions her granny arranged, and the lessons her granny tried to teach Elsa. I’m so glad to see Elsa success.</p><p>I agree that tell story is the best way to teach children. The children are full of imagination, and they love stories. If we build the stories with wisdom and knowledge, then they will remember. When they find the connection between tales and reality, they will find out that they have been told how to deal with the difficulties, and they will not be defeated.</p><p>I used to be popular to the children, and they all love me because they like my stories. Unfortunately, I have lost that ability. I think we adults all have that experience. Yesterday, we can tell tales without any preparation, but today, our mind is blank. That’s why we can’t be our children’s best friend.</p><p>This reminds me a movie called <code>Extremely Loud &amp; Incredibly Close</code>. Tom Hank plays a father named Thomas Schell. Thomas is a competent father who plays with his son every day back home. How I hope I have a father like him. May be that’s why I swear to be a good father. Well, I have no confidence right now. </p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/09/04/My-Grandmother-Ask-Me-To-Tell-You-She-s-Sorry-md/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monero</title>
      <link>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/08/21/Monero/</link>
      <guid>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/08/21/Monero/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 01:12:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s late for me to get start to know monero. But I just meet monero yesterday. I heard bitcoin in many years before, 
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Maybe it’s late for me to get start to know monero. But I just meet monero yesterday. I heard bitcoin in many years before, but I never want to learn about it. I think the conception is hard to understand. But we all know that bitcoin becomes more and more popular. As far as I know, Monero is another kind of bitcoin.</p><p>The best way to learn something is you start to have a try. So here I am.</p></blockquote><h1 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h1><p>Here’s the official introduction about Monero:</p><p>Monero is cash for a connected world. It’s fast, private, and secure. With Monero, you are your own bank. You can spend safely, knowing that others cannot see your balances or track your activity.</p><h2 id="Monero-is-secure"><a href="#Monero-is-secure" class="headerlink" title="Monero is secure"></a>Monero is secure</h2><p>Monero is a decentralized cryptocurrency, meaning it is secure digital cash operated by a network of users. Transactions are confirmed by distributed consensus and then immutably recorded on the blockchain. Third-parties do not need to be trusted to keep your Monero safe.</p><h2 id="Monero-is-private"><a href="#Monero-is-private" class="headerlink" title="Monero is private"></a>Monero is private</h2><p>Monero uses ring signatures, ring confidential transactions, and stealth address to obfuscate the origins, amounts, and destinations of all transactions. Monero provides all the benefits of a decentrallized cryptocurrency, without any of the typical privacy concessions.</p><h2 id="Monero-is-untraceable"><a href="#Monero-is-untraceable" class="headerlink" title="Monero is untraceable"></a>Monero is untraceable</h2><p>Sending and receiving addresses as well as transacted amounts are obfuscated by default. Transactions on the Monero blockchain cannot be linked to a particular user or real-world identity.</p><h2 id="Monero-is-fungible"><a href="#Monero-is-fungible" class="headerlink" title="Monero is fungible"></a>Monero is fungible</h2><p>Monero is fungible because it is private by default. Units of Monero cannot be blacklisted by vendors or exchanges due to their association in previous transactions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/08/21/Monero/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to earn more money?</title>
      <link>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/05/18/How-to-earn-more-money/</link>
      <guid>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/05/18/How-to-earn-more-money/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 03:17:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;Everybody need money, because money is essential to support our daily life. After my quit from last company, I have a financial problem. 
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everybody need money, because money is essential to support our daily life. After my quit from last company, I have a financial problem. It’s my salary just meet my expenses. Without more money, my life can’t overcome any unexpect things. Since then, the question is arrounding my head now and then - ‘How to earn more money?’.</p><p>I think most of you want more money, just like me. The rich are just a small group. Well, here’s the way I’m trying:</p><h2 id="1-Be-compentent-to-my-basic-job"><a href="#1-Be-compentent-to-my-basic-job" class="headerlink" title="1. Be compentent to my basic job"></a>1. Be compentent to my basic job</h2><p>My job is the fundamental financial source that assure me to support my family. So it’s the most important thing I keep in mind. No matter what job the boss asks me to do, I’ll do. and I will do it better than ordinary.</p><p>I don’t think I’m clever than others, but I’m sure I know a lot of higher efficient tools that helps me finish my work faster. So that I can save time to make difference. </p><h2 id="2-No-more-games"><a href="#2-No-more-games" class="headerlink" title="2. No more games"></a>2. No more games</h2><p>Playing games is the most import thing during my off hours, and I play with my wife and friends. It continues for almost two years. We even build a WeChat Group (<code>social APP, seems to twitter</code>) to invite others to join the game. Surely we enjoy it, and have a lot of fun. But We waste our time.</p><p>Finally, I’m determined to quit. No more Games, just focus on thinking and Studying. Up to now, I haven’t play games for 2 weeks, it feels good. Night seems longer than before.</p><h2 id="3-Write-Blog"><a href="#3-Write-Blog" class="headerlink" title="3. Write Blog"></a>3. Write Blog</h2><p>I recently read Mr. Wang’s Blog:<a href="http://home.wangjianshuo.com/20141024_ruanyifengs-message.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blog is Dead – Let’s Move On</a>. I was touched by his words: </p><blockquote><p>Now it is the time to re-think about the right tool to make some noise. I understand the desperate feeling of a Kong-Fu master see a gun. But the miracle always comes from the person who quickly learn to use the gun, instead of compete with gun by practicing Kong Fu hard.</p></blockquote><p>I agree with him. As a young man, I use WeChat to communicate with my friend. If China allows twitter or facebook, certainly I will choose them. I nearly read blog.</p><p>But I choose to write English Blog. I think it’ll help me improve my English, because I have no chance to use English on my daily life. And I hope to build contact with outside. Maybe this can make it possible. We’ll see.</p><h2 id="4-Do-amateur-projects"><a href="#4-Do-amateur-projects" class="headerlink" title="4. Do amateur projects"></a>4. Do amateur projects</h2><p>I’m plannig to do some projects on my spare time. First and most important, I’ll enhance my software programming skills. Second, this enriches my resume. Third, this may bring me money.</p><p>At last, I’m planning to develop a daily account software. I will give user more choices, such as windows desktop software, Android APP, web application, WeChat Mini Program. </p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/05/18/How-to-earn-more-money/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RaspberryPi-A tiny and powerful hardware</title>
      <link>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/04/03/RaspberryPi-A-tiny-and-powerful-hardware/</link>
      <guid>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/04/03/RaspberryPi-A-tiny-and-powerful-hardware/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:46:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a Pi, I have a Raspberry. Ah~ RasberryPi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;What-is-RaspberryPi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#What-is-RaspberryP
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>I have a Pi, I have a Raspberry. Ah~ RasberryPi.</p></blockquote><h2 id="What-is-RaspberryPi"><a href="#What-is-RaspberryPi" class="headerlink" title="What is RaspberryPi?"></a>What is RaspberryPi?</h2><blockquote><p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Raspberry Pi</a> is a series of small single-board computers developed in the United Kingdom by the Raspberry Pi Foundation to promote the teaching of basic computer science in schools and in developing countries.</p></blockquote><h2 id="What-can-RaspberryPi-do"><a href="#What-can-RaspberryPi-do" class="headerlink" title="What can RaspberryPi do?"></a>What can RaspberryPi do?</h2><p>I’m a software developer, so I just foucs on software application. I bought my Raspberry Pi Mode 3B on 2017-03-06. Here’s my applications:</p><ol><li>Build your own blog site.</li><li>Build your own version control system server.</li><li>Auto publish your own Book.</li><li>Auto send mails.</li></ol><h2 id="Build-your-own-blog-site"><a href="#Build-your-own-blog-site" class="headerlink" title="Build your own blog site"></a>Build your own blog site</h2><p>Using Hexo, you can build your own blog site in RaspberryPi.</p><p>Here’s the installation steps:</p><ol><li>Install node.JS and npm.</li><li>Install hexo-cli.</li><li>Init your blog directory.</li><li>Cfg your blog site.</li></ol><h2 id="Build-your-own-version-control-system-server"><a href="#Build-your-own-version-control-system-server" class="headerlink" title="Build your own version control system server"></a>Build your own version control system server</h2><p>Once upon a time, I tried to install GitLab in RaspberryPi, but failed. Because GitLab need higher computer performance, the Pi is not capable.</p><p>Then I turn to Gogs. Gogs is similar to GitHub, but it’s functions is not as many as GitHub’s. Gogs is just satisfy me.</p><p>Here’s the installation steps:</p><h2 id="Auto-publish-your-own-Book"><a href="#Auto-publish-your-own-Book" class="headerlink" title="Auto publish your own Book"></a>Auto publish your own Book</h2><p>I have a Kindle PaperWhite2. My Kindle accompany me during my daily time. So there comes a question: Why don’t I write my own book? Well, using Raspberry can help me finsh this goal. </p><p>Here’s the steps to publish your own Book:</p><ol><li>Write book;</li><li>Generate book;</li><li>Publish book.</li></ol><h3 id="Write-book"><a href="#Write-book" class="headerlink" title="Write book"></a>Write book</h3><p>I write my own book using MarkDown. </p><p>Why do I use MarkDown? Well, MarkDown helps me just focus on my writing, so I don’t need to worry about format. I just type the words, and Markdown Will show it in a neatly, beautiful views. If you don’t know Markdown yet, then I suggest you to get start to learn Markdown. You’ll not regret this.</p><p>My book will be saved with the suffix of ‘md’. Then We move to next step.</p><h3 id="Generate-book"><a href="#Generate-book" class="headerlink" title="Generate book"></a>Generate book</h3><p>When I say I want generate book, it means I want to convert Markdown file to MOBI file. </p><p>What is MOBI file? Well, the MOBI file is used to Kindle. </p><h3 id="Publish-book"><a href="#Publish-book" class="headerlink" title="Publish book"></a>Publish book</h3><h2 id="Auto-send-mails"><a href="#Auto-send-mails" class="headerlink" title="Auto send mails"></a>Auto send mails</h2>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/04/03/RaspberryPi-A-tiny-and-powerful-hardware/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/03/31/Introduction/</link>
      <guid>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/03/31/Introduction/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 06:10:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>
      
        
        
          &lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone! Today is worth remembering for me, since I finally start to build my own blog site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Who-am-I&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Who-
        
      
      </description>
      
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone! Today is worth remembering for me, since I finally start to build my own blog site. </p><h2 id="Who-am-I"><a href="#Who-am-I" class="headerlink" title="Who am I?"></a>Who am I?</h2><p>I’m a software engineer who loves coding and has much more interesting to new technology. Three years ago, I determined to be a full stack engineer, which seems impossible to me. Now I’m on my way. </p><p>I’m skilled with C, C++, MFC, Java, JavaScript, Docker, Jenkins, Node.js, and so on. Maybe it’s time now. I will try to combine these skills, make useful products.</p><h2 id="Thanks"><a href="#Thanks" class="headerlink" title="Thanks"></a>Thanks</h2><p>There’s an old saying, ‘A journey of a thousand miles begins with single step’. But I want to thank some person. Without them, without this blog.</p><p>First of all, I want to say thanks to my wife. Because she dose the most housework and cooks dinner for me, so that I can focus on my interest. And she encourages me when I feel down. It’s my lucky to marry her.</p><p>Second, I want to say thanks to my only pen-pal friend. We meet in about 7 years ago. She helps me to improve my English writing and gives me confidence. Because English is not my native language, I rarely pratice English on my daily life.</p><p>At last, I want to thank myself. Life is hard to ordinary people, including me. I have made too many choice at the cross roads. I thanks to myself to never give up, and rebuild my strength after every fails.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      
      <comments>http://longway2go.github.io/2018/03/31/Introduction/#disqus_thread</comments>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
